A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Culture Program, Program Staff Files FA639
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Education and Culture Program, Program Staff Files
1976-1984
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA639
1.2 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Subject Files, 1976-1984; I
  - Appropriations -- Education and Culture Biennial Budget Requests, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Benezet, Louis T. -- The Roles of Government and of Voluntary Accrediting Associations, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Center for International Communications Studies Proposal and Reports Re: International Institute of Communications, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Developing Countries Program Cultural Activities -- Incl. Sutton Paper Re: Foundations and Cultural Development, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Education and Culture Fiscal Year 1984 Budget Projection, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Board of Trustees/Future Program Planning Project (FPPP) -- Directory of Selected Foundations, Other Donors, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Field Offices -- Miscellaneous Trip Reports, Developing Countries Program Activities, etc., 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - Foreign Training Evaluation, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Foundation Library Committee Meeting, Nov 3, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Gladys Chang Hardy (GCH) -- Community Colleges, 1983 (Box 1)
  - GCH -- Geneva Meetings -- Human Rights and International Affairs, Jan 24-28, 1983 (Box 1)
  - GCH -- Meeting -- National Academy of Education (Boston), May 6-7, 1983 (Box 1)
  - GCH -- Meeting on Public Policy for Foundation Executives (Brookings Institution, Washington, D.C.), May 15-18, 1983 (Box 1)
  - GCH -- Summer Interns, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Humanistic Non-Fiction Writers -- RGAs, Memoranda, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Institute for the Study of Educational Policy (ISEP) -- Meeting (Washington and Capahosic, VA), Jun 18-20, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Interoffice Correspondence -- Urban Poverty/International Affairs/Developing Countries Program/Human Rights and Governance/Rural Poverty and Resources, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - Latin America -- Education and Culture and Jeffrey Puryear Paper Re: Education Research and Development Capacity, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Interoffice Memoranda and Report Re: Women at the Ford Foundation, etc., 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Myers, Robert -- Committee Report Re: Education of Third World Nationals, 1982 (Box 1)
  - National Women's Law Center -- Ford Foundation Funding, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Native American Consultancy, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Poland (desk file), 1982 (Box 1)
  - PRI -- Meeting Information and Project Lists, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - "Too Little, Too Late: Services for Teenage Parents" by Elizabeth A. McGee (working paper from the Ford Foundation), Oct 1982 (Box 1)
  - Trustees Information -- Meetings, Index of Information Papers 1951-1983, etc., 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Trustees Response Paper -- Education and Culture Status Report (draft), 1983 (Box 1)
  - Vice Presidents -- Miscellaneous Correspondence and Interoffice Memoranda Re: Ford Foundation Administration, Budget, Grants, etc., 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Women -- Ford Foundation Grants and Activities, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Women's Programs -- Memo Re: Special Appropriation for Women, Jul 15, 1983 (Box 1)